# Jerry D. House

Kansas City, Missouri

Phone: (816) 560-6214 | Email: jdhouse27@gmail.com

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/jdhouse1/">www.linkedin.com/in/jdhouse1/</a> | GitHub: <a href="mailto:github.com/jdhouse27">github.com/jdhouse27</a> |

Portfolio: <a href="https://jdhouse27.github.io/Portfolio/">https://jdhouse27.github.io/Portfolio/</a>

## **Summary**

Full Stack Developer with a background in healthcare, customer service, and retail. Leader by example with over 9 years of experience in clinical, technology, project management, and administrative positions. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Acknowledged by peers for attention to detail and determination towards successful project completion. Devoted to strengthening and refining professional effectiveness.

## **Technical Skills**

HL7 | CCL | SQL | MySQL | Node.js | Express | JavaScript | jQuery | React.js | GitHub | MongoDB | Passport.js | Firebase | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Various CSS Frameworks | Media Queries | APIs | JSON | AJAX | Handlebars | Microsoft Excel | Microsoft Office | Heroku | Project Management |

## **Projects**

Scenic | Code: github.com/jdhouse27/Project2 | Demo: oneprotwo.herokuapp.com/

- Project task was to design a full stack application where a user could easily find desired events/activities with a given specific location. User could then create a custom itinerary.
- Role: Project Lead Back-End Developer
- Tools: HTML5, CSS, UIKit, MySQL, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, API, Express, Heroku, GIT

#### Burger App | Code: github.com/jdhouse27/burger | Demo:eat-da-burger-jd.herokuapp.com/

- Game where users can dynamically create new burgers and devour with a simple click.
- Role: Full-Stack Developer
- Tools: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, MySQL, Express, Handlebars, GIT

#### **Bamazon** | Code: github.com/jdhouse27/bamazon | Demo: jdhouse27.github.io/bamazon/

- Online store using Node.js and MySQL database and queries.
- Role: Back-End Developer
- Tools: Node.js, MySQL

#### On the Ropes | Code: github.com/jdhouse27/unit-4-game | Demo: jdhouse27.github.io/unit-4-game/

- This application/game is a fun interactive game where users get to select a fighter and opponents to battle.
- Role: Front-End Developer
- Tools: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

#### Fuel Me Now | Code: github.com/jdhouse27/Fuel-Me-Now | Demo:jdhouse27.github.io/Fuel-Me-Now/

- Application designed for users to locate local gas stations and purchase gas for delivery.
- Role: Front-End Developer
- Tools: HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase, API, GIT

# **Experience**

#### **Support Analyst - Retail Systems Management**

April 2019-Present

- Troubleshoot issues, such as connectivity, hardware, or software issues ensuring successful and complete upgrade.
- Ensure correct connectivity throughout new site cluster system setup.
- Recover down machines due to failed Operating System image application.
- Reinstallation of Operating System, Printers, and other devices/software.
- Recover lost from network machines and reconfigure with correct IP address.
- Update/Resolve ServiceNow tickets.
- Documentation of solutions through SharePoint.

#### **General Manager/Owner Operator - Local Kansas City Restaurant**

May 2017-March 2019

- Ran day to day operations.
- Built strong team of motivated staff
- Maintained employee schedules to effectively decrease labor by 8%.
- Increased sales by 15% through guest and employee satisfaction.
- Maintained a quality product while controlling inventory costs.
- Responsible for training staff and maintaining proper staffing.

#### **Application Support Analyst - Mosaic Life Care**

March 2015-December 2018

- Maintained Data within large scale database on multiple servers.
- Wrote SQL queries for data retrieval, insertions, updates, and inactivation.
- Initialize and maintained various interfaces.
- Participant with Integration testing.
- Maintained workflow documentation with SharePoint.
- Created, updated, and resolved Jira work tickets.
- Collaborated with various departments for successful project management.
- Troubleshoot issues in an analytical and logical manor.

#### **Respiratory Therapist - Mosaic Life Care**

September 2009-March 2015

- Administered various Respiratory therapies to patients in ICU/ER/Surgery/MedSurg/Cardiac Floors.
- Set up and managed care of patients on ventilators closely with physicians and nurses.
- Trained department on new therapies and devices.
- Wrote and updated departmental protocols and procedures.
- Trained and oriented new respiratory therapists.
- Worked with Technology Services on charges and new orders.
- Worked with local colleges/universities in developing clinical rotations.

### **Education**

#### **Coding Bootcamp Certificate:**

Kansas University, Overland Park, KS

24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

# **Respiratory Therapy:**

Concorde Career College, Kansas City, MO

## (Associates Degree and Certificate)

18-month program followed by another 9-month program focused on gaining valuable lifesaving clinical knowledge of respiratory care.

#### **Neonatal Resuscitation Program:**

Children's Mercy Hospital, Kansas City, MO

NRP trainer certification